The credit for today's video goes to
this comment of Mr. Saurabh. Sir,
thank you for your comment. As you know,
every day every video on the channel
comes according to your questions, suggestions and comments. Therefore, to stay connected to the channel,
like and share the video. Do not forget to subscribe to the channel and turn on the
all notification bell.
Hello everyone, a very warm
welcome to all of you. You are watching You The
Real. I am your own personal advisor
Amitraj Sharma. In today's video, we are understanding the information about the Wealth Smart Plus plan of Aditya
Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited.
This plan is a unit linked
plan. Within this plan, you
get two different options. The first is Smart Life and the
second is Whole Life Option. In the plan,
you get five investment strategy options, in
which you get 19 fund options.
Before paying the premium, you
first choose the plan option, then choose the strategy
option, then choose the fund option. Then
you pay the premium to the insurance company. The
insurance company invests that premium
in the market as per your choice
and as soon as the policy term is completed, it
gives you the fund value.
Maturity  Which you can take in lump sum or installments. If it is a
market based plan
then the risk is yours and since it is a uly plan, hence the
life cover remains right during the policy term.
Okay, now comes the matter
of eligibility criteria of Wealth Smart Plus plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited.
If you take Smart Life Option
and if your child is even 30 days old
or more, then you will be
able to take the option for him. Smart Life Option:
People up to maximum 60 years
can take Smart Life Option. When it comes to Whole
Life Option, the minimum entry age limit has been
kept at 18 years i.e. 18 years and the
maximum entry age limit is 45 years
i.e. 45 years. The maturity age
limit for Smart Life Option is from 18
years to 75 years. The second
option is Whole Life Option, which means that till
you are 100 years old, you will be
able to remain under the cover under the plan. Okay, now
comes the matter Aditya  Talking about the
minimum sum assured limit of Wealth Smart Plus plan of Bilal Life Insurance Company Limited,
with Smart Life option,
if the age is between 30 to 50 years then it is
Rs.120000 and if it is more than that then it is Rs.84000. If you
take Whole Life option then at least
Rs.1020000 i.e. 10 times the annual premium.
Talking about the premium payment term,
with Smart Life option,
you get Limited Pay option from 5 years to 15 years. The
second is Regular Pay from 10 years to
40 years. In Whole Life option, there is only one
option of Limited Pay from 5 years to 15
years. If we talk about Regular Pay, then
from 100 you will subtract your age at the time of taking the plan. When it
comes to the policy
term, then the minimum policy term
with Smart Life option is 5 to 9 years. If you take premium payment term of 5 years to 9 years then you will
get it for 10 years, otherwise if the
premium payment term is more than this then the premium
payment term plus one year is yours.  The minimum
policy term will be 10 years with regular pay.
You will get a minimum policy term of 10 years. The maximum
policy term available is up to 40 years. If you
take the whole of the option, you have to
subtract your age from 100. The policy term will
come out. So, very
few people want to remain under the cover for such a long time. So,
most people
prefer to take the Smart Life option. When it comes to the
minimum premium limit, then with the annual
option, there is a limit of ₹1 with the forgiveness option. If you
like to pay the premium quarterly, then if you
like to pay in monthly installments, then ₹1
if you choose the monthly option, then
you get this premium mode only on the auto debit mode. When it
comes to benefits, in the uniting plan,
we know that as soon as the policy term is
completed, we get the fund value.
You can take the fund value in the plan in lump sum
or in installments for 5 years. When it
comes to death benefit, which
Your fund value at the time of the policy will be
compared. The partial withdrawals made in the
last two years will be deducted from the initial sum assured.
Then the comparison will be done.
105% of the total premium paid will be taken out and
105% of the base premium paid will be deducted from it. Out of these,
whichever is
higher among the three will be the death benefit, which the
nominee can take in lump sum or installments.
Okay, yes, the third benefit is
partial withdrawal. Now the
plan is available for minors as well. So the conditions here are the same as
in ULIP plans, that the
policyholder should be at least 18 years old
and the locking period of the policy of
first 5 years must be completed. The
minimum limit for partial withdrawal is
₹5000000
along with I am sorry for the maximum
withdrawal.  I had told you that the limit is
25% of the fund value, that is one time, that is the limit when you withdraw at one time,
otherwise you can withdraw only up to
50% of the fund value within a policy year
and all these
conditions apply to the systematic partial
withdrawal which you choose, either you
take parcel withdrawal or you
take systematic parcel withdrawal, if
you choose systematic parcel withdrawal
then you get a range of 5% of your fund
value or 10% of your fund value
annually, you
can take it in monthly or annual installments, you get free switches,
unlimited, if you choose self-managed
portfolio strategy, you get a
minimum of ₹5000000,
that is systematic transfer, now
what will happen in systematic transfer, the
premium that you pay here, that will be the net
premium, the insurance company will
first invest that premium in the liquid plus fund,
after that on a monthly
basis,
it will be transferred to the funds of your choice, that is  The
Liquid Plus Fund option is
your debt-oriented fund, which
is fixed. Apart from that, the other funds that you can
choose are Income Advantage, Enrichment Maximizer
Fund, Super 20 Fund, Cap Nifty Index Fund,
Multiplier Value and Momentum Fund,
Creator Fund, MNC Fund, ESG Fund, Small
Cap Fund and Nifty Alpha 50 Index Fund.
These are the other options that you
can choose under Systematic Transfer. You
can also choose more than one fund option, that is,
units will automatically be transferred from the Liquid Plus Fund to the fund of your choice every month. The second is Return Optimizer.
Now, as the name itself suggests, your
returns will be optimized so that the
risk in equity can be
reduced. This is an equity-based fund.
Here, Maximizer Fund, so as soon as your
premium goes into the Maximizer Fund and
if it increases by 10% or more, it should
increase by a minimum of 10%. If it increases by
more than this, then the growth will be
transferred
to the Income Advantage Fund so that
you do not see any downward movement in equity.
You are saved from this. Then the
third option is Self Manage, in which you get the
option of 19 funds, in which you
can choose any fund as per your wish
and can invest in any way you want,
but the allocation of your premium should be at least
5% in the fund. The
names of the 19 fund options available
are on the top of your screen, you can see:
Liquid Plus Fund, Income Advantage Fund, Ashore
Protector Builder, Anchor Creator,
Magnifier, Maximizer Multiplier, Super
20, Pure Equity Value and Momentum CAB,
Nifty Index Fund, Asset Allocation Fund,
MNC Fund, ESD Fund, Small Cap Fund and
Nifty Alpha 50 Index Fund. These are all the
19 funds which are available in this plan. The
fourth option comes here, your Smart
Investment Option of the portfolio. If you
choose the Smart Investment Option, then there are
two fixed funds in this option, in which the
first is Maximizer Fund, which is an
equity-based fund, the second is Income
Advantage Fund, which is depth-oriented.  The fund is here.
Now, here you get three portfolio options:
either you can be aggressive,
moderate, or conservation. Aggressive
means there will be more equity exposure.
Moderate means there will be equity
exposure but there will
also be debt-oriented options, and conservation will have
less equity exposure. Now, here the
outstanding term to maturity means the
time left for maturity.
Now, let us understand this like this:
if the policy term is 21 years or more and you
choose the aggressive option, then 90% of your premium will go
into the Maximizer Fund. The
remaining 10% will be invested in the Income Advantage Fund.
Then, in the next five
years, 80% will remain
in the Maximizer Fund, and the investment of the Income Advantage Fund will
increase by another 10%,
right, that is, it will become 20% here.
After that, in the next five years,
65% will be in the Maximizer Fund,
and 35% of your premium will be invested in the Income Advantage Fund.
And my  It
is believed that if you are taking a ULIP plan, then you should
remain in the aggressive mode and
exercise the equity option more, only then you will
benefit. With the aggressive option, in the
last three years,
only 20% will remain in the maximizer i.e. equity
and 80% of the investment i.e.
whatever fund value will be there will be
transferred to the Income Advantage Fund and whatever amount is
transferred here will be automatic.
You do not have to do anything, just pay the premium on
time and there is
no additional cost of any kind here.
However, if you want to switch
from aggressive to moderate or conservation during the term of the plan, you will be able to do so, there will be
no charge. The next option
is your life cycle investment option.
In this also, you get two funds -
Maximizer Fund and Income Advantage Fund. There are
three options for the risk profile of the same profile -
aggressive, moderate and conservative. Now, suppose the
age of the person taking the plan is
in the bracket of 1 year to 30 years, then
in such a case, 90%  The investment will be
in equity, i.e., the
Maximizer Fund. If the
Moderate option is chosen, then 70% will be
invested in the Maximizer Fund. The
remaining 30% will
go into the Income Advantage Fund.
In which, if the age is between 1 year and 30 years,
if the Conservation option is chosen, then the split will be
50-50. Income Advantage at 50
is Max Mother at 50, that is, Equity at 50,
Debt at 50. Now, the next age bracket is from 31
years to 40 years. People in this age group
also invest a lot
in ULIPs. Here, 80% will
remain in the Maximizer Fund.
If the Moderate option is chosen, then the remaining 60
% will remain in the Maximizer Fund. If the Income Advantage option is chosen, then the rest will be in Equity. If the
Income Advantage and Conservative option is chosen, then there will be a
50-50 split here,
as we know. Every
year, the fund manager automatically adjusts the
fund value.  You will have to pay for automatic rebalancing within the Maximizer Fund and Income
Advantage Fund.
Okay, now here comes the matter of
knowing about the charges of Aditya Willya Wealth Smart Plus Plan. So the
first main charge is our fund
management charge. If it is Liquid Plus
Income Advantage Ashor & Protector &
Builder Fund, then
you will be charged 1% of the fund value annually as fund management charge.
If it is Anchor Creator Cap Nifty
Index and Asset Allocation Fund, then you will be
charged 1.25% of the fund value annually.
MNC Magnifier Maxima I am sorry
Maxima R Maximizer Multiplier Super
20 Pure Equity ESG Fund Small Cap Fund
and Nifty Alpha 50 Index Fund Value
& Momentum Fund are the options on that because it is an
equity oriented fund dominated, so
here you will be charged an average fund management charge of 1.35% annually on your fund value.
On policy discontinuation, you will be charged
0.50% annual fund management charge on your fund value.
You do not have to pay premium allocation charge in this plan.
Policy Administration
You don't have to pay any charges in this, that is, the maximum of
your premium gets
invested directly in the fund here.
If you discontinue the policy within the first 4 years, then a
charge of ₹1000 to ₹6000 can be levied. The maximum will
depend on the year in which you are
discontinuing the policy and how much premium you were paying.
Mortality charge is levied according to your IU
gender and sum assured i.e. how much life cover you are
choosing. Now the question comes
that we want to know about 19 funds,
so how will we know? See,
I already made a video of Aditya Build Cell Life's Fuch Wealth
Plan. The same fund
option is available here as well which was in this plan. So
I have given the details of all these funds
in this video, including the 4tune Wealth
Plan video. We have given the link of that video
in the comment section of today's video, please check it out. There is
a new
option, Nifty Alpha 50 Index, its
details are not available yet, so we will use
its benchmark.  You will learn about this
through a case study given in the policy brochure. The
policy brochure states that
Mr. Sharma is 35 years old. He takes Aditya
Billa Sal Life's Wealth Smart Plus
plan. He chooses the Smart Life option and is
paying an annual premium of ₹1 lakh. The
premium payment term for 5 years is
20 years. He takes the Self-Managed
Portfolio Investment option
and is investing in the Nifty Alpha 50 Index Fund. In
such a situation, the life
cover he will get here will be
10 times the annual premium, i.e., the sum will be ₹1 lakh.
This is the amount. In case of
death, the nominee is
sure to get this much. If the rate of return is 8%, then after
completion of 20 years, the
amount can become around ₹14,989. If the
rate of return is 4%, then the
rate of return can become 8924. Meaning,
this much amount can be earned. Now the question arises whether a
return of 8% can be earned.  50
Index Fund, see Nifty Alpha which
is 50 Index Fund, this is the benchmark, so let
us know about this, whose
launch date was 19 November 2012 and base date was 2
December 2003, so the return given by Nifty Alpha 15 IX
Fund in the last 5 years was at the
rate of 39.26 per cent on average and since the
date of this Nifty Alpha 50 Index
Fund coming into existence till now, it has given a
rate of return at the rate of 23.12 per cent, so
definitely we can assume a rate of return of 8 per cent here
because it is a
ULIP plan, mortality rate etc. will be applicable,
rest there is no premium allocation charge
and there is no policy administration charge also,
so there are more chances that
your maximum premium will be invested in the market here, so if
you invest this much then you
can easily assume a rate of return of 8 per cent if you have chosen this fund
option, you can because
ULIP is a subject to market risk, you
guys watched the video patiently
Thank you very much for watching till the end,
many thanks. Now no matter how good any plan seems to you,
read the documents related to the plan. Do
not invest without understanding them.
Thank you for patiently watching the video till the end. If the information is clear then please
like and share the video.